<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cronocide.com</title>
    <link>https://cronocide.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on cronocide.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cronocide.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;daniel-dayley&#34;&gt;Daniel Dayley&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Experienced security and software engineer with with a history of technical and architectural leadership. Diversified skillset involving information security administration, software development, and system administration. Enthusiastic problem solver with a proven track record of technical growth and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-experience&#34;&gt;Work Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;network-security-engineer-qualtricshttpsqualtricscom&#34;&gt;Network Security Engineer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://qualtrics.com&#34;&gt;Qualtrics&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented automation to rotate TLS certificates in critical infrastructure equipment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented software IPSec VPN solutions for professional services customers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Designed and lead implementation of corporate Physical Two-factor Authentication (P2FA) strategy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Participated in security engineering hiring committees&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trained security engineers on various security tools and procedures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;infrastructure-security-engineer-slingtvhttpsslingtv&#34;&gt;Infrastructure Security Engineer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sling.tv&#34;&gt;SlingTV&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Designed, implemented and maintained network SIEM to monitor multiple datacenter infrastructures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Triaged, investigated and remediated network security incidents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Designed, implemented and demonstrated software PoCs for application vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Automated responses for common incidents and requests&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Created and directed patch management program&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;security-specialist-iii-utah-valley-universityhttpsuvuedu&#34;&gt;Security Specialist III (&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvu.edu&#34;&gt;Utah Valley University&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maintained workstation antivirus, PSI detection and Two-Factor Authentication on campus-owned computers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Created a PHP web frontend for Palo Alto&amp;rsquo;s IP list API&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Conducted and reported vulnerability assessments&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bachelor of Computer Science (&lt;a href=&#34;https://uvu.edu&#34;&gt;Utah Valley University&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-projects&#34;&gt;Personal Projects&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-hosting&#34;&gt;Self Hosting&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Currently maintaining over 50 virtualized and containerized application services orchestrated using Hashicorp tools. Example services include Git, VSCode, and Jenkins servers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;cronocide.net - hosting summary available with Google login at &lt;a href=&#34;https://status.cronocide.net/status/all&#34;&gt;https://status.cronocide.net/status/all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;security-conferences&#34;&gt;Security Conferences&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An active participant in local and global security and software development conferences, including UtahSAINT&amp;rsquo;s SaintCon, BSides SLC, BlackHat and Defcon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Presented at SAINTCON on Elasticsearch&amp;rsquo;s SIEM technologies, becoming the conference&amp;rsquo;s most popular tutorial: &lt;a href=&#34;https://crono.link/sc19&#34;&gt;https://crono.link/sc19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;uvu-cyber-security-club&#34;&gt;UVU Cyber Security Club&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While Vice President, designed, implemented, and managed enterprise training environments for students to exercise network security practices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2x 1st Place Competitor at Rocky Mountain Collegiate Cyber Defense competition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1st Place Competitor at NIATEC Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;serverless-apps&#34;&gt;Serverless Apps&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maildumpster - One Use Mail: &lt;a href=&#34;https://maildumpster.net&#34;&gt;https://maildumpster.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Crono.link - Personal URL Shortener: &lt;a href=&#34;https://crono.link/new&#34;&gt;https://crono.link/new&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;certificates&#34;&gt;Certificates&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CompTIA Network+&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CompTIA Security+&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CompTIA CySA+&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CompTIA Pentest+&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://apps.cronocide.com/login&#34; class=&#34;main&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;height:60rem&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building your first SIEM with the Elastic Stack</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/byfswtes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 08:47:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/byfswtes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This process is an exercise in installing and configuring Elastic Stack components for use as a SIEM. Normally you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t install all of these services on a single host: you should consider the resource consumption of each host and distribute your services appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After we get the basic software running we&amp;rsquo;ll do a few example searches and create an example alert. The power of your SIEM will be determined by how many detections you implement and what kind of alerts you use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacktober 2019 - Filesystems</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/hacktober2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 08:47:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/hacktober2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished the Hacktober 2019 CTF from the great folks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/uvucsc&#34;&gt;@UVUCSC&lt;/a&gt;. The challenges were mostly entry-level but there were a few that were quite challenging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The highest-point-value challenge was a frustrating and time-consuming monster developed by my friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ddbishop/&#34;&gt;chuck&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;code&gt;filesystems&lt;/code&gt;. I was the only solver of the challenge and was asked to do a write up of it, and because it was such a twisted and annoying challenge (that I learned a lot from) I decided to go ahead and do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable iMessage on Mac for ESXi (in 2017)</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/eiomfe17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/eiomfe17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running virtual Macs on ESXi is a great way to become familiar with the operating system and server software without buying your own Mac lab. To install MacOS on ESXI 5.5 and above is pretty trivial, since VMWare’s hypervisor almost natively supports the OS. There are several steps that must be done however before the OS will boot properly, and even still, before iMessage will work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install MacOS you will need a legitimate installer for the operating system, &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201372&#34;&gt;which can be produced by any Mac&lt;/a&gt; that has purchased the OS.&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Note: just because your Mac came with a specific version of MacOS doesn’t mean that you have it available in the app store. You must ‘purchase’ it for free before you can make installers for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Tabletop Arcade Cabinet with RetroArch on RetroPi</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/batacwror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/batacwror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each year I get a crazy idea for a great gift for one of my family members. I do my best to get everyone in my family something they’ll like or appreciate, but usually there is one person that I think ‘Wow, this would be a great gift for them!’. This year it was my Dad. On a day that I got lost on the internet I found that there was such a thing as &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=bartop+arcade+cabinet&#34;&gt;bartop arcade cabinet kits&lt;/a&gt; that take up a fraction of the space of normal arcade cabinets. My Dad has raved about getting a full-blown arcade machine for years but the progress on acquiring one has been slow. After carefully analyzing my budget for Q4 I decided I could just barely afford to build one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable 2FA SSH for Mac</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/e2sfm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/e2sfm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using two-factor authentication with &lt;a href=&#34;https://authy.com/&#34;&gt;Authy&lt;/a&gt; now for awhile and have really enjoyed the flexibility of being able to control all of my logins with 2FA. I got to thinking to myself “Wouldn’t it be cool if I could use 2FA on my SSH logins?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, it turns out that you can! I recently followed a tutorial by &lt;a href=&#34;https://servinglinux.com/articles/entry-pdf-export/1-secure-ssh-with-2fa/&#34;&gt;servinglinux.com&lt;/a&gt; and with little adaptation was able to get 2FA working beautifully on my Macs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrubbing File Metadata with exiftool</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/sfmwe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/sfmwe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The files that we upload and send all over the internet have a lot of data attached to them that we often forget about. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata&#34;&gt;metadata&lt;/a&gt; can tell others a lot about us that we don’t necessarily need other people to know. Picture files like JPEGs, PNGs, and even GIFs can hold metadata with custom values that show information about the history of the file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my case, I hate sending any technical information about my system to potential employers with embedded metadata in my job application. Since I use several different pieces of software to compose my resume and cover letters, I’d rather have that custom data scrubbed from the PDF files I make before I send it off to potential employers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Searching all your Mac’s downloads</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/saymd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/saymd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now and then I’ll download something and store it somewhere I can’t find later. Usually I rename downloaded files to something closer to what I think they ought to be called, and then forget what clever name I gave them. Sometimes I delete files that I can’t find the source for. For one reason or another, I lose downloads sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately your Mac keeps track of all the files you download. It keeps a database of the files coming into it and checks the files before letting you do much with them. I wrote a quick script to let you search these downloads and wanted to share it. Feel free to contribute anything you think would be helpful in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swapping Bytes with dd</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/sbwd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/sbwd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was reading in the &lt;code&gt;man&lt;/code&gt; page for &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; and found that some of the conversion options for it are kind of fun. One of these options, the swab conversion, swaps every two bytes of the input file and sticks them in the output file. The resulting file is usually not readable (if it is a binary) and pretty obfuscated if it is text. The usage is like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dd if=(input file) of=(output file) conv=swab&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Homebrew on Mac</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/ihom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/ihom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often receive complaints from developers and administrators about the lack of a centralized package system on the Mac. While Apple did provide &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Installer_(macOS)&#34;&gt;installer&lt;/a&gt;, the Darwin-era package installation app, it did not really have any sort of repository system until the App Store was released with Snow Leopard. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MacPorts&#34;&gt;MacPorts&lt;/a&gt;, the successor of DarwinPorts, was the de-facto package manager for enthusiasts for a long time. But in recent years a lot of the community has switched over to Homebrew for their package management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saving an ESXi Datastore from a Foreign Config</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/saedfafc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/saedfafc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My 3rd day of class started out with the unpleasant realization that my server was offline as of 4:30 this morning. I got the notice from my Uptime Robot who monitors the web server. I assumed that it was either a problem with my nginx frontend not starting automatically after a VM crash or a loss of internet to the house. Since I didn’t realize the problem until I was in class there wasn’t much I could do. My VPN has been a work-in-progress, and I now realized that the work on that particular project needs to get finished soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Vagrant Box on Mac</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/suavbom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/suavbom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year I’ll be working with several different operating systems for school. I want to run each of them as natively as I can on my production machine without having to un-boot my production Mac environment. Virtualization is the obvious answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re anything like me you’ve always been turned off by the graphical interfaces for Virtualbox and VMWare. Personally, I’ve always preferred to work in a command-line environment anyway. I’m going to use something called &lt;code&gt;vagrant&lt;/code&gt; to boot a pre-configured VM and get me SSH’ed into it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edit Mac Terminal Prompt</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/emtp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/emtp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you SSH around different devices running varying operating systems and shells you see quite a variety of shell prompts. I’ve decided that my prompt should give me the username and host of the machine I am trying to connect to, as well as the full path of the working directory. This way the prompt is always ready to be copied for an &lt;code&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt; argument. I’ve decided that I want to standardize my prompts with this information, and it’s pretty easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/repo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;apt-repository&#34;&gt;Apt Repository&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository has packages I&amp;rsquo;ve built for Linux and iOS.&#xA;These packages are offered &lt;em&gt;AS IS&lt;/em&gt; and include &lt;em&gt;no warranty&lt;/em&gt; or obligation of support.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;cydia://url/https://cydia.saurik.com/api/share#?source=https://cronocide.com/repo&#34;&gt;Add to Cydia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;packages&#34;&gt;Packages&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;Version&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cronocide.com/repo/pool/main/c/com.cronocide.hostname/com.cronocide.hostname_1.0.0_iphoneos-arm.deb&#34;&gt;hostname&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;1.0.0&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;iphoneos-arm&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
