<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on cronocide.com</title>
    <link>https://www.cronocide.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on cronocide.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 08:47:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.cronocide.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building your first SIEM with the Elastic Stack</title>
      <link>https://www.cronocide.com/post/byfswtes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 08:47:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cronocide.com/post/byfswtes/</guid>
      <description>Preface This process is an exercise in installing and configuring Elastic Stack components for use as a SIEM. Normally you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t install all of these services on a single host: you should consider the resource consumption of each host and distribute your services appropriately.
After we get the basic software running we&amp;rsquo;ll do a few example searches and create an example alert. The power of your SIEM will be determined by how many detections you implement and what kind of alerts you use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktober 2019 - Filesystems</title>
      <link>https://www.cronocide.com/post/hacktober2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 08:47:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cronocide.com/post/hacktober2019/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished the Hacktober 2019 CTF from the great folks @UVUCSC. The challenges were mostly entry-level but there were a few that were quite challenging.
The highest-point-value challenge was a frustrating and time-consuming monster developed by my friend chuck called filesystems. I was the only solver of the challenge and was asked to do a write up of it, and because it was such a twisted and annoying challenge (that I learned a lot from) I decided to go ahead and do it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>