<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on cronocide.com</title>
    <link>https://cronocide.com/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on cronocide.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cronocide.com/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shoot Into the Wild Bluesky</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/boi2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/boi2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a journey to complete my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bsky.app/&#34;&gt;Bluesky&lt;/a&gt; account setup for over a year now. The content loss I experienced as a result of the evaporation of my Infosec Twitter community in 2022 was largely mitigated by my massive &lt;em&gt;(and unhealthy)&lt;/em&gt; Reddit diet at the time, but when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/apollo-and-other-popular-third-party-reddit-apps-have-shut-down-123149140.html&#34;&gt;they shut down 3rd party apps&lt;/a&gt; I knew the time had come for me to do some &lt;em&gt;major&lt;/em&gt; social media readjustments. I started the setup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://bsky.app/profile/cronoci.de&#34;&gt;my Bluesky account&lt;/a&gt; back in 2023 but only barely got around to finishing setting it up today. As I re-read the docs for setting up the account I re-organized the information around the ideas of ownership in Bluesky and thought I would jot down some quick learnings on the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacktober 2019 - Filesystems</title>
      <link>https://cronocide.com/post/hacktober2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 08:47:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cronocide.com/post/hacktober2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished the Hacktober 2019 CTF from the great folks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/uvucsc&#34;&gt;@UVUCSC&lt;/a&gt;. The challenges were mostly entry-level but there were a few that were quite challenging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The highest-point-value challenge was a frustrating and time-consuming monster developed by my friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ddbishop/&#34;&gt;chuck&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;code&gt;filesystems&lt;/code&gt;. I was the only solver of the challenge and was asked to do a write up of it, and because it was such a twisted and annoying challenge (that I learned a lot from) I decided to go ahead and do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
